And that's when she looked down
and realize she was wearing purple socks with the burgundy dress!
Purple and burgundy, darlings!
The same color family!
That was a terrifying story.
Yeah, I'm terrified she'll try to tell it again.
Anyone else have a spooky story?
I have one.
But I'm warning you, you might as well hug your friend now.
That's how scary it is!
Oh, dear.
It's time I told you about the legend of Gaia Everfree.
Many years ago my great grandparents came to this forest.
Seeing its beauty, they decided that it would be the perfect place for a camp.
But once they started building, strange things started to happen.
One pitch-black night, when the wind was howling,
a tree branch crashed through the roof of their cabin.
They screamed and ran outside,
only to see the giant creature rising from the earth.
She got wild hair, like the roots of a tree.
Her mouth had jagged rock teeth and her eyes were pools of black tar.
But her aura shimmered like diamonds.
Anywhere she went, she left a trail of gemdust in her wake.
Trembling, my great grandparents asked who she was and what she wanted.
In a deep and hollow voice she told them that her name was Gaia Everfree –
an ancient spirit who held domain over the forest,
and that my great grandparent were trespassing on her land.
They begged her to let them stay and build their camp
to share this wonderful place with others.
Gaia Everfree finally agreed,
but warned them that they would not be able to keep it forever.
Some day she will return and reclaim the forest as her own.
So if you see a trail of gemdust, you'll know that it is...
Gaia Everfree!
Hey, guys! Sorry, didn't mean to scare you!
Then why did you come out of the bushes?
I... took the scenic route, because the forest is beautiful at night.
But no one else should without a guide, okay?
Alright, everybody, time to head to you tents.
Oh, hey, Gloriosa.
Do you have extra toothbrushes? I forgot mine.
Sure do! I'll get one for you.
I'm scared of the dark! Do you have flashlights?
Of course! I got this!
Fluttershy?
Sorry, Spike. I guess that story got to me.
Why? It can't be real.
I don't know.
Gaia Everfree some creature that got booted from Equestria
and ended up in this world
That's what happened with the Sirens.
Eh. Sounded more like something that Timber was making up just to scare us.
At least I hope it was.
Last thing I want is to have camp ruined by some power-crazed magical creature.
Oh, hear-hear.
We had to deal with more than our fair share of those.
At the Fall Formal, a musical showcase, the Friendship Ga–
Well, I mean, you know, everything turned out alright, of course
Mmm. I'm kinda tired. I'm in a turn in.
Maybe lay off bringing up what happened at the Friendship Games?
I think she's still pretty sensitive about it.
Our lips are sealed.
Here I am!
Over here.
I'm always here!
No!
Who's there? What happened?
Nothing. Sorry, Sunset.
Uh, Twilight, I think something happened.
Is it time to get up already?
Twilight, we really have to talk about this.
No, we don't!
Hey, I know you don't want to,
but I really think we need to figure out what's going on with your magic.
If you could learn to control it–
That's just it! I'll never be able to control it!
What happened?
I didn't mean to!
We didn't see anything, so we don't know what happened.
Are you okay?
Yeah. It was so weird.
We were stuck in a middle of the lake with no wind,
then all of a sudden BAM!
The wind picked up and we were pushed right into the dock.
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
No, it was me.
Spirit, show yourself!
The Great and Powerful Trixie commands it!
What's that?!
Oh, man! All our hard work! Ruined!
At least the fishes are really well.
Let's salvage what we can out of the water.
Maybe we can still fix this?
We have to try! Camp Everfree needs our runway!
Dock.
Dock, yes, that's what I meant.