So many squirrels.
Spike?
Ah! Oh, aw man!
I was having the best dream.
Wait, that dream could be a reality!
Before you run off to chase squirrels,
do you have any idea where Twilight could be?
I really need to talk to her.
What happened?
Did you do that lifting things off the ground again?
That's just it, I don't know if it was her,
but if it was, we need to deal with it head on.
I can track her down.
Keep it together. Deep breaths.
You are not a monster.
Oh, hi.
What are you doing here?
Uh, looking for you.
Oh, I just went on a nature walking, got a little lost.
Let me show you the way.
I'm kind of an expert at these woods.
I've lived here my whole life.
That must have been nice.
Growing up at a camp.
Yeah, though it has its downsides.
When I was younger I wish we would sell this place
so we can live in a town like normal people.
Really?
I was ten. I really wanted to hang out in the mall.
I've never told that to anyone.
You must be special.
And not just because you have tree branch in your hair.
Uh. How long has that been in there?
Not long. Just the whole time we were talking.
Then why didn't you say something?
I guess we can help Twilight deal with the magic stuff a little later.
Rope climbing is all perseverance and trust.
Rarity, you can trust that Applejack will spot you.
Yeah, so you can totally go faster than you're going.
Rainbow Dash!
Sorry. I've been waiting to do this since we got here.
Well, you have to wait a little longer, darling.
Oh, good!
Twilight, if you spot me, I can finally go.
I'll go get another harness.
I'm not sure–
I'll better make sure my sister doesn't need anything.
See you later.
Twilight, there you are!
I was looking for you!
Was than an earthquake?
We aren't near any fault lines.
Hey! Who left this crystally dusty stuff here?!
I-I believe I'd like to come down now!
Sorry, it's a little bit stuck.
Applejack! What are you doing?!
Is everything okay over there?
Uh, I don't know what happened.
I didn't even pull the rope that hard.
It's like she was light as a feather all of sudden.
I was scared half to death!
It wasn't my fault! Let me get your harness out.
No, thank you!
What in the world just happened?!
Oh, dear! I am so sorry! I think.
Did I just do... whatever that was?
I don't think it was your fault.
I need to get Applejack a towel.
Me too.
You're not the only one with a new kind of magic!
This is great!
No, it's not!
Rarity and Applejack could have really hurt each other!
Why is this happening? I don't–
Hi, girls! Anything I can do for you?
Uh, Applejack just fallen to the lake!
Oh, no!
She's gonna need warm towels, dry clothes, oh, and a hot cocoa!
I've got this!
Fluttershy?