Did you?
How is this possible?
I can't believe this.
It's...
- Amazing!  - Terrible!
Are you kidding?
This is great!
I mean, we've all ponied up before,
gotten the whole ears and wings and tail thing,
shot magical rainbow lasers,
but nothing like this has ever happened!
How did you do it?
I don't know!
Maybe I didn't.
Maybe it's her!
Her who?
Nothing.
Nevermind.
Can we just not talk about it?
And could you please not bring this whole levitating thing up to the others?
Why not?
You heard Applejack.
This is supposed to be the place where everyone can get away from magic.
I don't want them to know I brought some crazy new kind with me.
If you really don't want me to, I won't say anything.
I really don't.
Okay, but this isn't necessarily a bad thing!
I think you're just gonna have to pick it up.
-show up like that!
What did you say?
I... didn't say anything.
Just here to make everyone was headed over to the docks!
Did you need something?
Nope.
Because if there is anything I can do
to make this week the best week ever,
you just let me know.
I've got this!
Thanks, I'm good.
People that chipper make me nervous.
This is gonna be so much fun!
I guess not all people.
Oh, it's beautiful, isn't it?
It looks like a diamond shining in the sun!
It is lovely out here.
The fresh air, the cool breeze,
the birds that land on your finger.
I think that only happens to you.
Lake activities are available every day until sunset,
so if you want to canoe, sail, windsurf, or swim, just let me know.
Aren't they just the cutest?
Whoa! I know I'm charming,
but you don't have to fall for me.
Guess I can't get too jealous, right?
After all, she isn't my Twilight.
Not that the other Twilight was mine!
But we were... you know.
Yeah. I get it.
But your Twilight is a princess in Equestria
Hate to break it to you,
but that's where she's gonna spend most of her time.
So you're saying I just need to get over her?
Kinda, yeah.
Ouch. You're not pulling any punches.
Not really my style.
Sorry.
This is a safety hazard.
I suggest we close down the dock for the remainder of the camp.
Oh, I'm sure it won't have to be for the remainder of the camp.
Just needs to be patched up a bit.
I've got this!
Huh. Or maybe we do!
If you ask me, this whole dock needs to go.
Building a new one could be our camp gift.
Sure, it would benefit us,
but a nice new dock would benefit future campers, too.
I don't know.
It's an awful lot of work.
I wouldn't want you guys to miss out doing other fun camp stuff,
because you're so busy building a dock for future campers.
I hear what you're saying, Timber,
but we're Canterlot Wondercolts!
We've got a reputation to uphold!
And there was no way we're gonna leave this place
without contributing the most awesome camp gift ever!
I'm with AJ, building a new dock is definitely it!
What do you guys think?
Looks like it's settled, then.
Looks like it.
That's some tension all right.
We can reinforce foundation.
Make it nice and sturdy.
And we can add a wood-carved sign that says "Camp Everfree".
And little boxes with food
so you can feed the ducks and fishies.
Oh, we'll add lanterns so you can see at night!
It's stunning!
And will make an absolutely perfect runway for my camp fashion show!
More importantly,
it will be a great place for docking canoes and feeding the wildlife.
Oh, you say "tomato",
I say "perfect place to showcase glamorous boho-chic stylings".
What do you guys think?
It's going to be a lot of work, but we can do it!
Yes! Adult supervision!
Huh, nice hammer.
Where did you get it?
Un, duh. The toolbox?
Hah, that's cool.
I made mine.
Ugh.
Making lanterns out of solar-powered garden lights!
Pretty crafty there, Timber!
You think that's crafty?
You should see my macaroni art.
I'm like the Picasso of noodles.
Alright, now.
You've made a lot of progress.
But it's going to be getting dark soon.
We can pick this up tomorrow between our other camp activities.
Everyone, get cleaned out,
and we'll gather by the fire pit at eight to share s'mores and scary stories!
S'MORES!!!