What happened?!
I don't know, we were just decorating cookies and–
And I was all
"You need more sprinkles! And you need more sprinkles!"
So, standard Pinkie Pie stuff.
I was just tossing sprinkles to Fluttershy,
when all of a sudden they glowed pink and exploded!
Just like that, only earlier!
Oookaay, why don't you lay off touching stuff for a while?
Oh, dear.
We really should clean all of this up.
Can someone help me out?
Thank you, mister bird.
Why, of course I can get you little something to–
Did you just... talk?
But I don't speak "chirp".
I don't know if you're the only bird I can understand.
Oh, no!
Please don't call for your friends.
It's nice to meet all of you, too.
Were you just talking to the birds?
Um, yes?
Did you tell them what happened?
So crazy!
I hoisted up Rarity up the rock climbin' wall like it was nothing!
Like I had way more strength than I usually do.
And I made diamondy thing appear out of nowhere,which normally I'd be excited about.
I mean, the facets were just perfect.
And the–
Rarity!
Oh, sorry.
It knocked Applejack over and then it disappeared!
Speaking of disappearing, has anybody seen Rainbow Dash?
Ow!
Whoa! How did you do that?
I don't know.
I've started running to get the harness
and the next thing I knew I was practically back in town!
But if you had some sort of superspeed
why you were gone for so long?
Because I lost it when I got far away.
And then it came back when got close to camp.
Being at camp is giving us all new magical abilities!
Not all of us has gotten new abilities.
I haven't, but Twilight– hasn't, either.
So much for my theory
that leavin' CHS would mean leavin' any new magic business behind.
Something at the camp must be making this happen.
Um, Gaia Everfree?
Applejack! I was looking for you!
Here, I brought you some towels and dry clothes.
Uh, what happened in here?
We're kinda trying to figure that out.
Well, don't worry about it. I've got this!
Gloriosa, I kicked my beanbag into the lake!
I'll get you another one!
And I'm all out of arrows!
Say no more! New arrows coming right up!
There you are!
Filthy Rich is back.
Do you want me to handle it?
Absolutely not! I got this!
Fluttershy, enough with the screaming!
I didn't scream.
For once.
Nobody did.
Huh?
Attention, campers!
Anyone who's interested in making floating paper lanterns
please meet us by the picnic tables.
I don't know about the rest of y'all,
but I've been lookin' forward to comin' here for a month.
Maybe we forget about this new magic for a bit
and just try to focus on enjoyin' our time at camp?
I was oh, so excited about designs I've come up with for the camp fashion show.
And I've barely gotten to whoop anybody in tetherball.
I think we should try to figure it out.
But if letting it go for now is what the rest of you want...