Um, Pinkie Pie, what are you doing?
Putting marshmallows in my lantern.
Then when we light them, mine will be beautiful and delicious!
Hey, Twilight, why aren't you with everyone else?
Sunset said something at camp is causing the other girls to get new magic.
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
She's still part of me.
I can feel it.
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know what I can do.
Okay, everyone!
It's time to watch your lanterns fly!
Hey, cool lantern!
Mine's my face.
Uh, you okay?
Mm-hmm.
You don't seem like yourself tonight.
Ready?
And... go!
Aw! Oh well!
Now I get to eat it!
Yep, Beautiful and delicious.
Twilight?
Twilight!
Where is she going?
Twilight?
What are you doing out here?
We're... we're meeting a cab to take us home.
She thought you'd talk her out of it.
Because I would.
Twilight, you can't leave.
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
No, it was me.
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
She's still part of me.
I can feel it.
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
Twilight, there's no Midnight Sparkle.
There's only you.
How did you know what I was thinking?
When I touched your hand, I can see things.
I can understand why you were leaving.
My new magic!
This is my new magic!
This is incredible!
No, it's not.
I'm infecting you now!
Twilight, you have to stop looking at this as a bad thing.
Easy for you to say.
Magic turned you into something beautiful.
The last time I tried to use it,
it turned me into a monster.
I'm just so afraid it's gonna happen again.
Yes, last time I turned into something amazing,
but I've let magic turn me into a monster, too.
So if anyone understands what you're going through, it's me.
I can help you, Twilight.
And the rest of our friends can be there for you, too.
But not if you run away.
I'll stay.
I still don't think this is a good idea for me
to be near the rest of our friends right now.
Not until we know why this is happening.
Understood.
What was that?!
Wait. Twilight?
Timber?
I'm so glad it's just you!
Wait, what are you doing out here?
With an axe?
I was chopping down firewood.
In the middle of the night?
We needed more for tomorrow night's campfire.
And if I didn't take care of it tonight,
it would be one more thing Gloriosa would add to her list.
I've got this!
What about you two?
Why are you hanging out in the woods in the middle of the night?
Oh, I was sleepwalking.
Twilight found me and was bringing me back to camp.
Mm-hmm.
Come on, I'll walk you guys back.
I'll protect you from Gaia Everfree!
Everfree! Everfree!
Come on,
that's obviously just a spooky story you made up to tell around the campfire.
Oh, no.
It's legit.
How else would you explain what happened at the docks?
And that weird thing when the earth shook?
Uh, come on, I know a shortcut back to the tents.
Legit, huh?
I think we just found our "Gaia Everfree".
But why would he work so hard to make us think she was real?
You heard what he said
about wishing his sister would sell this camp.
If nobody wants to come here,
because it's home to some angry ancient nature spirit,
it sure would help his cause.
We should tell Twilight.
Not yet.
She's obviously going on through a lot right now.
We should probably be a hundred percent sure
before we tell her the guy she likes is a jerk
who's trying to run everybody out of camp.
Uh-huh!
Phew!
Uh, you gonna give us a hand here, Rarity?
Oh, I'd love to,
but I really need to get the stitching on this poncho done
before it's going to make it into the camp fashion show.
Though at the pace you two are moving,
I don't know that the runway will ever be finished.
The dock is our gift to the camp
and it's gonna get finished.
That is if Rainbow Dash would hurry up and bring me more wood.
Oh, I can't go any faster!
I don't want to end up in the woods again.
Don't be silly.
Really?
I know I said we should try to forget all about this new magic business,
but I can't.
What if I hammer the board into splinters?
Aw, shoot!
I'm all out of nails.
Oh, here you go!
Pinkie, no!
What?
Ohhh, did you think that nails would explode like the sprinkles?
Wow! Glad that didn't happen, huh?
Sorry, girls.
I didn't mean to
And I don't know how to control this.
It's okay.
Oh, none of us do.
Which is why we shouldn't pretend this isn't happening.
Do you have them now, too?
It's started last night.
When I touch people,
it's like I can feel what they're feeling and see their memories.
Oooh, fancy! Try me, try me!
La-la-la-la. Ooh, taffy!
That explains so much.
Yep.
Girls, we can't just brush these powers aside
because it doesn't seem like the ideal time to get them.
What if it turns out that they could actually make things better?