No.
It can't be.
It isn't true.
Um, Twilight?
Twilight!
The bus for Camp Everfree leaves in ten minutes!
Oh no no no no no!
I can't believe I overslept!
Me neither. That's not like you.
I know!
Don't you have a super-annoying alarm clock that goes omm-omm-omm-omm?
It's gonna be fine.
We'll help you pack.
Eh.
We're gonna be out in the woods.
When's she gonna need that?
If we were going to the moon, I'd insist she'd pack an evening gown.
One never knows, darling.
Lemme just get changed.
Midnight Sparkle?!
How is this possible?
Sunset Shimmer helped me defeat you at the Friendship Games!
You and your friends can never truly defeat me!
Midnight Sparkle's a part of you!
I'll always be there,
waiting in the darkest shadows of your mind!
I'll be back, Twilight!
And this time, I won't stop until I have all the magic!
No!
STOP!
Twilight, wake up!
We can't stop, silly!
We're not there yet!
Hey, are you okay?
Heh. I'm fine.
We are gonna have so much fun!
We're gonna roast marshmallows and eat marshmallows and sleep on marshmallow pillows!
Yeah, probably not gonna do that.
Maybe you're not.
Attention, students,
we're almost there.
But before we arrive,
we just wanted to say how proud we are of you for raising enough money to go on this class field trip.
When we were your age, we made some of our favorite memories in these woods,
and we're sure you will, too.
Now who's excited for Camp Everfree?!
习成 PBU 工作组
制作
蛟龙
Loadhe & BronyDee
监制
Will you be lost by time or be part of history?
Pinkiesparkle & 蛟龙
爱飞的 502
合作翻译
Will your story be told or remain a mystery?
奈吉尔 & 狼王.shadow
ruzx007878
合作翻译
Will they sing your song, telling all that you have done?
HF & 彳亍游龙
合作翻译
Time to make your choice, only you can be the one
Pinkiesparkle & LeafyBat
润色
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
LeoDango
润色
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
JT
质量管理
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree
Hey Hey Hey
Will you do something great with the time that you have here?
BronyDee & 蛟龙
时间轴
Will you make your mark, will you conquer what you fear?
And when you go back home, everybody there will see
You were part of the Legend of Everfree
TD & 爱飞的 502
狼王.shadow
时间轴
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
BronyDee
压制
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
Will you find your greatest glory?
饰 暮光闪闪
饰 余晖烁烁
Will you be a falling star?
饰 云宝黛西 & 苹果杰克
Here to learn what nature teaches
饰 萍琪派 & 小蝶
Here to learn more who you are
Will you be lost by time or be part of history?
饰 瑞瑞
Will your story be told or remain a mystery?
饰 斯派克
And when you go back home, everybody there will see
饰 嘉兰金菊
You were part of the Legend of Everfree
饰 云杉棕木
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
As you join in the Legend of Everfree (Hey)
As you join in the Legend of Everfree
Hey
Isn't Camp Everfree just beautiful?
I can't wait until we have our first nature walk.
I definitely wanna go on one of those.
You wanna see all the adorable woodland creatures, too?
Yeah! Specifically squirrels!
More specifically, so I can chase 'em!
I'm just lookin' forward to roughin' it.
I'm gonna make my own shelter, forage for food...
Uh, you know they provide us with food and tents, right?
Yup!
Still gonna forage though.
I'm just after some R & R.
The past year has all been a bit too much for my taste.
I'll say!
We fought three evil sirens who tried to hypnotize everybody with their singing,
one ridiculously competitive rival school,
and two demon friends!
Uh, heh heh,
no offense.
None taken.
You'll get used to it.
Yep.
Canterlot High has become a regular magic magnet.
Gonna be nice gettin' away to a place where we don't have to worry about that kinda stuff.
Here you go, Twilight.
Thanks.
It's Flash, right?
Yup, that's me!
And you're you.
And we don't know each other very well.
Cool story, bro.
Right.
I guess I'll... see you around.
You know how there's that girl who looks just like you
hen she's here but lives in another dimension and she's a pony princess?
Uh-huh.
Flash kinda had a... thing for her.
Oh.
Hey, everyone!
If you could start heading to the courtyard, that would be rad!
It's time to start the best week of camp ever!
Hi, everyone! Welcome to Camp Everfree!
I'm Gloriosa Daisy, your camp director!
Think of me as your friendly camp and nature guide.
And this is my brother, Timber Spruce!
Think of me as that awesome guy...
who should always be invited to fun things.
We aim to please, so before we hand out our tent assignments,
we'd like to hear from all of you.
You're free to do whatever you like here!
Uh, except hike near the rock quarry.
That's off-limits.
Yes, but otherwise, your options are wide open.
So what activities will make this the very best week of your lives ever?
Ooh! Rock climbing!
Done!
Archery!
Of course!
Tetherball!
Naturally!
Rainbow, I know you're excited,
but maybe give somebody else a chance to make a suggestion.
Arts and crafts!
My mom... needs new pot holders.
I'll supply the looms!
Cookie decorating!
Ooh, I do make a mean sugar cookie.
Early morning nature walks?
With walking sticks for everyone!
Ooh! Me! Oh, uh...
a fashion show!
Where I design the most fabulous camp looks
inspired by today's hottest trends
and have them modeled by my classmates in a gorgeous outdoor setting!
A camp tradition!
We have literally never done that.
I'll be taking requests the rest of the time you're here,
so if there's anything you'd like to do,
anything you need,
just ask.
What about the camp gift?
That was my favorite Camp Everfree tradition.
The camp gift! Of course!
Really?
Yes, really.
Well, I just thought-
Then you thought wrong!
Anyone else picking up on a little tension between Gloriosa and her brother?
Ehhh...
A little.
Every year, campers work together to create something useful.
A gift for future campers.
Working toward this common goal is key to forming the strong bonds
that will last well beyond your time here at camp!
Which is why it's so important.
This gazebo was a gift from last year's group.
Oh, oh, oh, and the totem pole
and the sundial were also made by campers!
The sundial was our year's gift!
Even though "some people" thought it was a little impractical,
since the sundial can't be used at night.
Oh, you all seem like a-a really amazing group.
So I'm certain you'll come up with something inspiring to leave behind.
Speaking of leaving things behind,
now's the time when we give out tent assignments
so you can leave your heavy bags behind.
Uh, girls will be getting their assignments from Timber.
Guys, you're with me.
Oh, boy!
Yay! I'm in the Emerald Tent!
Ooh, me, too!
Aquamarine.
Me, too!
Yee-hoo!
I got Amethyst.
Sapphire.
Me, too!
I mean, I'm assuming I am.
Technically, sapphires aren't just blue.
They can be pink,
purple,
yellow...
Yeah, but they're mostly blue.
That's why they're named after the Latin word sapphirus.
That means "blue".
I know.
But did you know that sapphires are just rubies without chromium?
No.
But did you know that Sapphire Tent is the best one?
Why's that?
Because you're in it.
Oh, I bet you say that to all the campers.
Not true.
You're in the Ruby Tent?
Ha! That's the worst one!
Aw, man!
I'm just jokin', buddy.
Ruby Tent is great.
It's like a sapphire, but with chromium.
But the Ruby and Coral Tents do look an awful lot alike to the undiscerning eye.
I better show you where it is.
See ya around.
What?
Heh.
Nothin'.
That was adorable!
Okay, everyone, go get settled in.
We'll be meeting at the docks in fifteen minutes
to go over some camp safety rules.
Let me know if you need anything!
I need somethin'.
Filthy Rich!
So nice to see you.
What are you doing here?!
Camp is just getting started!
Just takin' in the scenery, Gloriosa Daisy.
It's so...
hmm...
relaxin'.
Well, you can look around when camp is over!
Now, if you don't mind...
Fine.
Filthy Rich is, uh, an alumni of the camp.
He likes to check on his old stomping grounds every now and again.
But enough about him.
Find your tents and put away your things.
We've got the best week of camp ever to begin!
I'm all for learning safety rules,
but I do hope I can get started on my designs for the camp fashion show sooner rather than later.
Huh. I still can't believe you talked Gloriosa into havin' a fashion show.
We're in the middle of the woods, for cryin' out loud!
We're s'posed to be roughin' it!
It's clear from Gloriosa's own wardrobe
that she appreciates a well put together look.
Even if we are in the "middle of the woods".
Fair enough.
Just as long as you don't put me in one of your fancy pants outfits.
You're gonna, aren't ya?
No.
Yes! Don't worry, darling.
It'll absolutely speak to your personal sense of style...
That was weird back there, right?
With that guy, Filthy Rich?
Huh?
Oh. Uh, I guess so.
I just have this feeling that Gloriosa's hiding something.
Her brother is pretty cute, though, huh?
He's okay.
Ooooh,
now look who's trying to hide something!
No, I'm not!
Hey, you okay?
You seemed a little freaked out on the bus earlier.
Probably had another one of her nightmares.
I'm fine.
I mean, what do I have to complain about?
Ever since I transferred here, everyone from CHS has been really nice and accepting,
especially considering what happened at the Friendship Games.
That wasn't your fault.
Principal Cinch is the one who encouraged you to try and use all that magic to win the Games for Crystal Prep.
You weren't ready to have that kind of power.
But it's over now.
And if there's any group that's gonna forgive you for something that happened in the past,
trust me, it's this one.
You guys comin' or what?
Be right there!
I just wanna put on some sunscreen.
Huh. I Coulda sworn I packed it.
Found it!
Did you?
How is this possible?
I can't believe this.
It's...
- Amazing!  - Terrible!
Are you kidding?
This is great!
I mean, we've all ponyed up before,
gotten the whole ears and wings and tail thing,
shot magical rainbow lasers,
but nothing like this has ever happened!
How did you do it?
I don't know!
Maybe I didn't?
Maybe it's her?!
Her who?
Nothing.
Nevermind.
Can we just not talk about it?
And could you please not bring this whole levitating thing up to the others?
Why not?
You heard Applejack.
This is supposed to be the place where everyone can get away from magic.
I don't want them to know I brought some crazy new kind with me.
If you really don't want me to, I won't say anything.
I really don't.
Okay, but this isn't necessarily a bad thing!
Omm... Omm...
I think you just gotta have to pick it up.
...show up like that!
What did you say?
I... didn't say anything.
Just here to make everyone was headed over to the docks!
Did you need something?
Nope.
Because if there is anything I can do
to make this week the best week ever,
you just let me know.
I've got this!
Thanks, I'm good.
People that chipper make me nervous.
This is gonna be so much fun!
I guess not all people.
Oh, it's beautiful, isn't it?
It looks like a diamond shining in the sun!
It is lovely out here.
The fresh air, the cool breeze,
the birds that land on your finger.
I think that only happens to you.
Lake activities are available every day until sunset,
so if you want to canoe, sail, windsurf or swim, just let me know.
Aren't they just the cutest?
Whoa! I know I'm charming,
but you don't have to fall for me.
Guess I can't get too jealous, right?
After all, she isn't my Twilight.
Not that the other Twilight was mine!
But, we were... you know.
Yeah. I get it.
But your Twilight is a princess in Equestria,
hate to break it to you,
but that's where she's gonna spend most of her time.
So you're saying I just need to get over?
Kinda, yeah.
Ouch! You're not pulling any punches.
Not really my style.
Sorry.
This is a safety hazard.
I suggest we close down the dock for the remainder of the camp.
Oh, I'm sure it won't have to be for the remainder of the camp.
Just needs to be patched up a bit.
I've got this!
Huh. Or maybe we do!
If you ask me, this whole dock needs to go.
Building a new one could be our camp gift.
Sure, it would benefit us,
but a nice new dock would benefit future campers, too.
I don't know.
It's an awful lot of work.
I wouldn't want you guys to miss out doing other fun camp stuff,
because you're so busy building a dock for future campers.
I hear what you're saying, Timber,
but we're Canterlot Wondercolts!
We've got a reputation to uphold!
And there's no way we're gonna leave this place
without contributing the most awesome camp gift ever!
I'm with AJ, building a new dock is definitely it!
What do you guys think?
Looks like it's settled, then.
Looks like it.
That's some tension alright.
We can reinforce foundation.
Make it nice and sturdy.
And we can add a wood-carved sign ’This is Camp Everfree.‘
And little boxes with food
so you can feed the ducks and fishes.
Oh, we'll add lanterns so you can see at night!
Oh, it's stunning!
And will make an absolutely perfect runway for my camp fashion show!
Or importantly,
it will be a great place for docking canoes and feeding the wildlife.
Oh, you say tomato,
I say perfect place to showcase glamorous boho-chic stylings.
What do you guys think?
It's going to be a lot of work, but we can do it!
Yes! Adult supervision!
Huh, nice hammer.
Where did you get it?
Em, duh! The toolbox?
Hah, that's cool.
I made mine.
Guh.
Making lanterns out of solar-powered garden lights!
Pretty crafty there, Timber!
You think that's crafty?
You should see my macaroni art.
I'm like the Picasso of noodles.
Alright, now!
You've made a lot of progress.
But it's going to be getting dark soon.
We can pick this up tomorrow between our other camp activities.
Everyone, get cleaned out,
and we'll gather by the fire pit at eight to share s'mores and scary stories!
S'MORES!!!
And that's when she looked down
and realize she was wearing purple socks with the burgundy dress!
Purple and burgundy, darlings!
The same color family!
That was a terrifying story.
Yeah, I'm terrified she'll try to tell it again.
Anyone else have a spooky story?
I have one.
But I'm warning you, you might as well hug your friend now.
That's how scary it is!
Oh, dear.
It's time I told you about the legend of Gaia Everfree.
Many years ago my great grandparents came to this forest.
Seeing its beauty, they decided that it would be the perfect place for a camp.
But once they started building, strange things started to happen.
One pitch-black night, when the wind was howling,
a tree branch crashed through the roof of their cabin.
They screamed and ran outside,
only to see the giant creature rising from the earth.
She got wild hair, like the roots of a tree.
Her mouth had jagged rock teeth and her eyes were pools of black tar.
But her aura shimmered like diamonds.
Anywhere she went, she left a trail of gemdust in her wake.
Trembling, my great grandparents asked who she was and what she wanted.
In a deep and hollow voice she told them that her name was Gaia Everfree –
an ancient spirit who held domain over the forest,
and that my great grandparent were trespassing on her land.
They begged her to let them stay and build their camp
to share this wonderful place with others.
Gaia Everfree finally agreed,
but warned them that they would not be able to keep it forever.
Some day she will return and reclaim the forest as her own.
So if you see a trail of gemdust, you'll know that it is...
Gaia Everfree!
Hey, guys! Sorry, didn't mean to scare you!
Then why did you come out of the bushes?
I... took the scenic route, because the forest is beautiful at night.
But no one else should without a guide, okay?
Alright, everybody, time to head to you tents.
Oh, hey, Gloriosa.
Do you have extra toothbrushes? I forgot mine.
Sure do! I'll get one for you.
I'm scared of the dark! Do you have flashlights?
Of course! I got this!
Fluttershy?
Sorry, Spike. I guess that story got to me.
Why? It can't be real.
I don't know.
Gaia Everfree some creature that got booted from Equestria
and ended up in this world
That's what happened with the Sirens.
Eh. Sounded more like something that Timber was making up just to scare us.
At least I hope it was.
Last thing I want is to have camp ruined by some power-crazed magical creature.
Oh, hear-hear.
We had to deal with more than our fair share of those.
At the Fall Formal, a musical showcase, the Friendship Ga–
Well, I mean, you know, everything turned out alright, of course
Mmm. I'm kinda tired. I'm in a turn in.
Maybe lay off bringing up what happened at the Friendship Games?
I think she's still pretty sensitive about it.
Our lips are sealed.
Here I am!
Over here.
I'm always here!
No!
Who's there? What happened?
Nothing. Sorry, Sunset.
Uh, Twilight, I think something happened.
Is it time to get up already?
Twilight, we really have to talk about this.
No, we don't!
Hey, I know you don't want to,
but I really think we need to figure out what's going on with your magic.
If you could learn to control it–
That's just it! I'll never be able to control it!
What happened?
I didn't mean to!
We didn't see anything, so we don't know what happened.
Are you okay?
Yeah. It was so weird.
We were stuck in a middle of the lake with no wind,
then all of a sudden BAM!
The wind picked up and we were pushed right into the dock.
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
No, it was me.
Spirit, show yourself!
The Great and Powerful Trixie commands it!
What's that?!
Oh, man! All our hard work! Ruined!
At least the fishes are really well.
Let's salvage what we can out of the water.
Maybe we can still fix this?
We have to try! Camp Everfree needs our runway!
Dock.
Dock, yes, that's what I meant.
It used to be so simple
It was a world I understood
I didn't know what I didn't know
And life seemed pretty good
But now the darkness rises
From somewhere deep inside of me
Her power all but takes me
Can I keep this midnight from getting free?
If I can stay in the light
I know I'll be free
Then I can start to be whole
I can start to be me
But instead I am struggling
With all that I see
And these friends
Mustn't see the midnight in me
The midnight in me-ee
They mustn't see the midnight in
Meeeee
So many squirrels.
Spike?
Ah! Oh, aw man!
I was having the best dream.
Wait, that dream could be a reality!
Before you run off to chase squirrels,
do you have any idea where Twilight could be?
I really need to talk to her.
What happened?
Did you do that lifting things off the ground again?
That's just it, I don't know if it was her,
but if it was, we need to deal with it head on.
I can track her down.
Keep it together. Deep breaths.
You are not a monster.
Oh, hi.
What are you doing here?
Uh, looking for you.
Oh, I just went on a nature walking, got a little lost.
Let me show you the way.
I'm kind of an expert at these woods.
I've lived here my whole life.
That must have been nice.
Growing up at a camp.
Yeah, though it has its downsides.
When I was younger I wish we would sell this place
so we can live in a town like normal people.
Really?
I was ten. I really wanted to hang out in the mall.
I've never told that to anyone.
You must be special.
And not just because you have tree branch in your hair.
Uh. How long has that been in there?
Not long. Just the whole time we were talking.
Then why didn't you say something?
I guess we can help Twilight deal with the magic stuff a little later.
Rope climbing is all perseverance and trust.
Rarity, you can trust that Applejack will spot you.
Yeah, so you can totally go faster than you're going.
Rainbow Dash!
Sorry. I've been waiting to do this since we got here.
Well, you have to wait a little longer, darling.
Oh, good!
Twilight, if you spot me, I can finally go.
I'll go get another harness.
I'm not sure–
I'll better make sure my sister doesn't need anything.
See you later.
Twilight, there you are!
I was looking for you!
Was than an earthquake?
We aren't near any fault lines.
Hey! Who left this crystally dusty stuff here?!
I-I believe I'd like to come down now!
Sorry, it's a little bit stuck.
Applejack! What are you doing?!
Is everything okay over there?
Uh, I don't know what happened.
I didn't even pull the rope that hard.
It's like she was light as a feather all of sudden.
I was scared half to death!
It wasn't my fault! Let me get your harness out.
No, thank you!
What in the world just happened?!
Oh, dear! I am so sorry! I think.
Did I just do... whatever that was?
I don't think it was your fault.
I need to get Applejack a towel.
Me too.
You're not the only one with a new kind of magic!
This is great!
No, it's not!
Rarity and Applejack could have really hurt each other!
Why is this happening? I don't–
Hi, girls! Anything I can do for you?
Uh, Applejack just fallen to the lake!
Oh, no!
She's gonna need warm towels, dry clothes, oh, and a hot cocoa!
I've got this!
Fluttershy?
What happened?!
I don't know, we were just decorating cookies and–
And I was all
"You need more sprinkles! And you need more sprinkles!"
So, standard Pinkie Pie stuff.
I was just tossing sprinkles to Fluttershy,
when all of a sudden they glowed pink and exploded!
Just like that, only earlier!
Oookaay, why don't you lay off touching stuff for a while?
Oh, dear. We really should clean all of this up.
Can someone help me out?
Thank you, mister bird.
Why, of course I can get you little something to–
Did you just... talk?
But I don't speak chirp.
I don't know if you're the only bird I can understand.
Oh, no!
Please don't call for your friends.
It's nice to meet all of you, too.
Were you just talking to the birds?
Um, yes?
Did you tell them what happened?
So crazy!
I hoisted up Rarity up the wall climbing wall like it was nothing!
Like I had way more strength than I usually do.
And I made diamondy thing appear out of nowhere,which normally I'd be excited about.
I mean, the facets were just perfect. And the–
Rarity!
Oh, sorry.
It knocked Applejack over and then it disappeared!
Speaking of disappearing, has anybody seen Rainbow Dash?
Ow!
Whoa! How did you do that?
I don't know.
I've started running to get the harness
and the next thing I knew I was practically back in town!
But if you had some sort of superspeed
why you were gone for so long?
Because I lost it when I got far away.
And then it came back when got close to camp.
Being at camp is giving us all new magical abilities!
Not all of us has gotten new abilities.
I haven't, but Twilight– hasn't, either.
So much for my theory
that leaving CHS would mean leaving any new magic business behind.
Something at the camp must be making this happen.
Um, Gaia Everfree?
Applejack! I was looking for you!
Here, I brought you some towels and dry clothes.
Uh, what happened in here?
We're kinda trying to figure that out.
Well, don't worry about it. I got this!
Gloriosa, I kicked my beanbag into the lake!
I'll get you another one!
And I'm all out of arrows!
Say no more! New arrows coming right up!
There you are!
Filthy Rich is back.
Do you want me to handle it?
Absolutely not! I got this!
Fluttershy, enough with the screaming!
I didn't scream.
For once.
Nobody did.
Huh?
Attention, campers!
Anyone who's interested in making floating paper lanterns
please meet us by the picnic tables.
I don't know about the rest of y'all,
but I've been looking forward to coming here for a month.
Maybe we'll forget about this new magic for a bit
and just try to focus on enjoying our time at camp?
I was also excited about designs I've come up for the camp fashion show.
And I've barely gotten to whoop anybody in tetherball.
I think we should try to figure it out.
But if letting it go for now is what the rest of you want...
Um, Pinkie Pie, what are you doing?
Putting marshmallows in my lantern.
Then when we light them, mine will be beautiful and delicious!
Hey, Twilight, why aren't you with everyone else?
Sunset said something at camp is causing the other girls to get new magic.
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
She's still part of me.
I can feel it.
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know what I can do.
Okay, everyone!
It's time to watch your lanterns fly!
Hey, cool lantern!
Mine's my face.
Uh, you okay?
Mhm.
You don't seem like yourself tonight.
Ready?
And... Go!
Aw! Oh well!
Now I get to eat it!
Yep, beautiful and delicious.
Twilight?
Twilight!
Oh, where is she going?
Twilight?
What are you doing out here?
We're... we're meeting a cab to take us home.
She thought you'd talk her out of it.
Because I would.
Twilight, you can't leave.
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
No, it was me.
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
She's still part of me.
I can feel it.
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
Twilight, there's no Midnight Sparkle.
There's only you.
How did you know what I was thinking?
When I touched your hand, I can see things.
I can understand why you were leaving.
My new magic!
This is my new magic!
This is incredible!
No, it's not.
I'm infecting you now!
Twilight, you have to stop looking at this as a bad thing.
Easy for you to say.
Magic turned you into something beautiful.
The last time I tried to use it,
it turned me into a monster.
I'm just so afraid it's gonna happen again.
Yes, last time into something amazing,
but I've let magic turn me into a monster, too.
So if anyone understands what you're going through, it's me.
I can help you, Twilight.
And the rest of our friends can be there for you, too.
But not if you run away.
I'll stay.
I still don't think this is a good idea for me
to be near the rest of our friends right now.
Not until we know why this is happening.
Understood.
What was that?!
Oh, wait. Twilight?
Timber?
I'm so glad it's just you!
What are you doing out here?
With an axe.
I was chopping down firewood.
In the middle of a night?
We needed more for tomorrow's campfire.
And if I didn't take care of it tonight,
it would be one more thing Gloriosa would add to her list.
I've got this!
What about you two?
Why are you hanging out in the woods in the middle of a night?
Oh, I was sleepwalking.
Twilight found me and was bringing me back to camp.
Mhm.
Come on, I'll walk you guys back.
I'll protect you from Gaia Everfree!
Everfree! Everfree!
Come on,
that's obviously just a spooky story you made up to tell around the campfire.
Oh, no.
It's legit.
How else would you explain what happened at the docks?
And that weird thing when the earth shook?
Uh, come on, I know a shortcut back to the tents.
Legit, huh?
I think we just found our Gaia Everfree.
But why would he work so hard to make us think she was real?
You heard what he said
about wishing his sister would sell out the camp.
If nobody wants to come here,
because it's home to some angry ancient nature spirit,
it sure would help his cause.
We should tell Twilight.
Not yet.
She's obviously going on through a lot right now.
We should probably be one hundred percent sure
before we tell her the guy she likes is a jerk
who's trying to run everybody out of camp.
Uh-huh!
Phew!
Uh, you gonna give us a hand here, Rarity?
Oh, I'd love to,
but I really need to get the stitching on this poncho done
before it's going to make it into the camp fashion show.
Not to haste you two with moving.
I don't know that the runway will ever be finished.
The dock is our gift to the camp
and it's gonna get finished.
That is if Rainbow Dash would hurry up and bring me more wood.
Oh, I can't go any faster!
I don't want to end up in the woods again.
Don't be silly.
Really?
I know I said we should try to forget all about this new magic business,
but I can't.
What if I hammer the board into splinters?
Aw, shoot!
I'm out of nails.
Oh, here you go!
Pinkie, no!
What?
Oh, did you think that nails would explode like the sprinkles?
Wow! Glad that didn't happen, huh?
Sorry, girls.
I didn't mean to
And I don't know how to control this.
It's okay.
Oh, none of us do.
Which is why we shouldn't pretend this isn't happening.
Do you have it now, too?
It started last night.
When I touch people,
it's like I can feel what they're feeling and see their memories.
Oooh, fancy! Try me, try me!
Lalalala. Ooh, taffy!
That explains so much.
Yep.
Girls, we can't just brush these powers aside,
because it doesn't seem like the ideal time to get them.
What if it turns out that they could actually make things better?
So you have magic
And it's not that great
But when it found you
You know it was fate
And it might seem scary now
But it can be wonderful, too
So, how about we embrace the magic
And make the magic part of you
You take a little dash of magic
And you let it ignite
Mix things up a little bit
And it might start to go right
In just five seconds flat
How the story has changed
All cause now you've embraced the magic
And it just got better in every way
I say embrace the magic
No more holding back, just let it out
If you can take the magic
And learn a little more what it can do
Once the magic is part of you
What's standing in your way
That you can't move today?
You've got the strength in you
To make your dreams come true
No need to shield yourself
From the magic that can help
Protect from any harm
That might come
So you have magic
And it's not that great
But when it found you
You know it was fate
So, if you listen close
You might make a new friend
And together we can make it!
I say embrace the magic
No more holding back, just let it out
If you can take the magic
And learn a little more what it can do
Once the magic is part of you
Once the magic is part of yoooou
Okay, that was pretty awesome!
And look what you managed to accomplish!
Please, please, please
can we do a run-through for the fashion show on it right this minute?
Thought you weren't finished with the stitching on your poncho
I am now
Get started without me
I've gotta go find Twilight
Seeing what we've been able to do here might make her embrace the new magic, too!
Uh, not that she has any
I just wish you didn't tell them that ridiculous story!
Ah, this is all too much for you!
You have to let it go!
I knew it!
He wants her to get rid of the camp!
Ugh!
Sunset Shimmer?
What were you doing behind that door?
What?
Um, nothing!
I, um, lost an earring. Uh, there it is!
Hey, listen
I'm glad I ran into you
I really wanted to thank you
For what?
For the tough love
Telling me I should get over Twilight
I needed to hear that
Sure, no problem
Is something wrong?
What?
No. Why?
Come on, Sunset
We used to date
I know when something's bothering you
Okay, here's the deal
My friend really likes someone
but I don't think that someone is who she thinks they are
I don't wanna upset my friend by telling her what I think
because I also want to protect her
because if what I think is happening is really happening
then she deserves to know
You know?
Nnnno
But what I do know is that your friend is lucky
to have someone like you to look out for them
Really?
Yeah
You know, you've changed a lot since we went out
You're so much... nicer
Thanks. I'm glad you noticed
Uh, look, maybe you and me
we could start over as... friends
Uh, uh, sounds great
I gotta go!
Cool, yeah!
I want to start over later, too!
Ah, shoot!
He's definitely up to something!
It's Sunset
She says to meet her by the rock quarry
I thought we weren't supposed to hike out that far
She says it's important!
What is that?
Shhh!
What's going on down there?
I think it's Gaia Everfree
Or rather someone who wants us to think she's back
C'mon!
Whoa...
This place is beautiful
There's Equestrian magic here
I can... I can feel it
Wait
I thought Timber was just faking there was a magical nature creature
Are you saying it's real?
Timber?
What does he have to do with any of this?
Nothing
It's all me
Gloriosa?
But... Timber
I was sure he was the one
trying to make it seem like Gaia Everfree was back
It was you who was trying to scare everyone away?
I would never try to scare anyone away from Camp Everfree
My, oh my
You fell behind on your payments, Gloriosa
I own the land now
Please, my great grandparents founded this place
It's been in our family for generations!
You have to let the camp stay!
Instead of turning it into a spa resort
that will line my pockets with more money than this camp ever could?
I don't think so
Please!
I-I-I-I just need a little more time!
Fine. I'll give you 'til the end of the month
Humph
What'll I do?
Huh?
Oof
Wow!
You don't know what those things are!
But I know what they can do!
I've been practicing!
I can control their power now!
You don't know that for sure!
This is our camp, and it's being taken away!
If this has to be our last week here
I'm going to use whatever it takes to make it count!
You were using magic all over the place!
I had to tell them something to cover for you!
What did you want me to do?!
I just wish you didn't tell them that ridiculous story!
Ah, this is all too much for you!
You have to let it go!
Timber wasn't talking about letting go of the camp
He was talking about you letting go of the magical geodes!
All those things you were doing to make this week the best week ever
Every time you used magic to do them
you caused another problem somewhere else!
Timber was... covering for you!
How do you know what I was doing with the geodes?
How do you know about the magic?
I can see things
Feel things
Because I have magic, too
And so does she
And so do our friends
Gloriosa, Timber wasn't wrong
Maybe you should stop using magic?
Too much of it can be dangerous if you can't control it!
Oh, I got this!
And I'm going to use it to save my camp
I just need more power!
No!
Sorry, girls
I know what I need to do
But I feel like we're not on the same page
So...
Gloriosa!
No!
Where are Twilight and Sunset?
They're missing our dress rehearsal
Uh-uh
I suppose we can get started without them
Whenever you're ready!
Hmm, Told you you'd like it
It's alright... I guess
I do get to keep it after camp though, right?
She looks... different
Yeah. She looks... taller
This is only a preview
I've got another entire line I'll debut at the real thing
Why did you stop the–
Oh my goodness!
Attention, campers!
It's Gaia Everfree!
She's real!
Aah! We're doomed!
Gloriosa?!
What are you doing?!
That's Gloriosa?
Am I going crazy or are her feet not touching the ground?
Freaky-deaky!
I have an announcement to make!
Filthy Rich wants this to be the last session of Camp Everfree
But don't worry
I got this!
Oh, come on!
We literally just finished building that!
I have waited for the day
To send this greedy wolf away
Now the magic is my salvation
Gather close in my protection
We will stand for Everfree!
Behold the beauty of nature in all its glory
No need to fear the vultures at the door
Right here you have me to protect you
Within these walls of thorns
For Everfree for evermore!
They have come into our domain
Here to seal our camp in chains
But we have held it for generations
This is just a complication
We will stand for Everfree!
Trust in me, this is for your own good
Don't be afraid
Nature is our friend
All of this beauty that surrounds us
Every lovely bloom designed to defend
Let them come! Just let them try!
I'm not about to say goodbye!
This camp will be here throughout the ages
Written into the history pages
We will stand for Everfree!
Oh, why do these kinds of things always happen to us?
What are we going to do?
What we always do!
Save the day!
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy!
This is gonna be so much fun!
Oh! I only wish we had time to make superhero capes!
Oh, me too!
Enough about our wardrobe!
We've got to stop Gloriosa from trapping everybody in here!
Um, hi
Do you think you can give us a hand–
Um, er, paw? We could really use a way out
This isn't working!
Her magic is too strong!
Nice work, Spike!
Twilight, you have to use your magic!
I don't think I can lift something that big
It's our only chance of getting out of here
and helping our friends!
Why are you fighting me?
I'm doing this to save our camp!
I'm doing this for you!
Gloriosa, let's just think about this for a moment, shall we?
I mean, I think Camp Everfree is absolutely delightful
but I just don't know that if I'm quite ready to give up my weekly trips to the spa.
To the spa
TO THE SPA?!
Gloriosa, this isn't the way!
I appreciate your concern, Timber
BUT I GOT THIS!
No, you don't!
Twilight, do you think you can use your magic?
I don't wanna use too much
Midnight Sparkle could take over
Twilight, our friends are in there!
Okay
Please, Gloriosa
What you're doing is crazy
You have to listen to me!
That isn't Gloriosa
Twilight!
Sunset!
You're okay!
That isn't your sister
It's someone who's been consumed by Equestrian magic.
Whoever you are, you have to let my sister go!
Please, Gloriosa, come back!
I need you!
Gloriosa!
Rarity!
I can't keep this up forever!
It's up to you
You can use your magic to pull the brambles apart!
No. There's too many of them
It would take too much magic. I can't!
It's the only way!
You have to embrace the magic inside you!
What if she takes over?
What if instead of saving everyone
I turn into Midnight Sparkle and only make things worse?
That won't happen!
We won't let it
Come on, Twilight!
You have to be stronger than she is!
You will never control me! I will always be a part of you!
Nooo!
Twilight, listen to me! You are in charge!
You are a light, darling! A force for good!
Yeah! You can kick the darkness's butt!
We're here for you, Twilight!
And we'll be here no matter what!
We believe in you!
You are not Midnight Sparkle!
No! I am Twilight Sparkle!
And the magic I carry inside me is... the Magic of Friendship!
No! Stop!
Gloriosa?
What... What happened?
It's okay
It's gonna be okay
You did it!
Oh, nice bling
What... What are these?
I'm not sure
But clearly we have some kind of connection to them
I almost don't care what they are
They are gorgeous!
And will totally go with the other collection I was working on for the camp fashion show!
That's probably cancelled, isn't it?
I am so sorry
I only wanted this to be the best week Camp Everfree has ever had
Then instead I've made it the worst
Maybe it's for the best that I'm losing the camp to Filthy Rich
No, it's not
This camp has meant so much to so many people
my sister and me included
Why do you think we wanted our students to come here?
We can't let Filthy Rich take this place away!
If camp meant so much to you two
maybe it meant as much to the other campers who came here in years past
And maybe we can get them to help save it!
Oh! Like a fundraiser?
Or a ball?!
Our band could play!
I can help writing a new song just for the occasion!
Those are all good ideas, but where would we hold it?
We can hold it in the crystal cave!
A Crystal Ball! I'm on it!
I admire everyone's enthusiasm
Really, I do
But I-I just don't know how we're going to plan a ball by tomorrow
and invite everyone
We got this!
I used to think that stories were just that
Set in stone, concrete as a fact
It didn't dawn on me
That I could change history
Now I know I'm writing my own song
Fight my way to the ending that I want
I'll turn a tragedy
Into an epic fantasy
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You can be a hero too
Oh-oh-oh
Take my hand, I'm here for you
Come away with me
Be the legend you are meant to be
You'll always be
Everfree
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
To be the legend you are meant to be
There was a time when fear would hold me down
'cause I let it chain me to the ground
Look at me now, I'm soaring high
It's never boring in the sky
When I know I've got friends on my side
Whatever trials I'll take them all in stride
Together we will shine so bright
Radiant brilliance in the night
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You can be a hero too
Oh-oh-oh
Take my hand, I'm here for you
Come away with me
Be the legend you are meant to be
You'll always be
Everfree
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
To be the legend you are meant to be
Thank you all so much for coming
And for helping us raise enough money to... save Camp Everfree!
Thank you For everything
Oh, if I'd just asked for help in the first place...
Heh, don't sweat it, it's kinda what we do
Not to brag or anything
but it's pretty cool how I saved all those campers from those Rubus fruticosus
Blackberry brambles
I'm familiar with the genus
it's just a little weird you say you saved the campers
I thought I saved them
Yeah
But I saved you from falling on the docks
so that you can save the campers
So technically, it was all me
I'm really glad I met you
Uh-oh
What?
That sounds like a goodbye
And here I was hoping we'd still be able to hang out
Maybe get dinner and catch a movie?
Yeah. I'd really like that
Oh, good!
I was hoping that's what this meant
Oh, uh, sorry
I need to borrow Timber
There are some donors I really want him to meet
They were good friends with mom and dad
Save me a dance, okay?
Uh-huh
Adorable
He does seem like a pretty cool guy
You know what else is cool?
Our awesome new superpowers!
I handed out, like, four hundred fliers
set up the stage
and still had time to pick up pizza
I love my superspeed!
About that
I think the crystals are the source of the superpowers
You're not gonna ask us to give them up, are you?
No
In fact, I think maybe we were meant to have them all along?
Me too
There is one thing I'm still wondering about, though
What's that?
Where did the magic that hit this cave come from?
Somewhere's a book
With chapters still blank inside
It's the book of our lives
And the story is ours to write
Some pages fade
While others are black and white
And the story begins
Again every time we try
Every time we try
And hope shines eternal
And friends are all I need
And the future is always bright
When you're here with me
I fought through the darkness
And come out the other side
For rain clouds will clear
The way for the sunny skies
I've been afraid
And stayed through the longest nights
But morning still comes
And with it, it brings a light
And hope shines eternal
And friends are all I need
And the future is always bright
The future is always bright
Yeah, the future is always bright
When you're here with me